#### Contact

xd.davidevans@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/davidevans-42653813 (LinkedIn) devansxd.netlify.app/ (Portfolio)

## Top Skills

User Experience Web Development jQuery

#### Certifications

Foundations of UX: Making the Case for Usability Testing

# **David Evans**

Senior Interaction Designer at UK Home Office United Kingdom

## Summary

I have worked as a design lead in the public sector for 4 years and am passionate about embedding high standards of design across teams, growing potential in junior colleagues, and delivering world class services and products to citizens and government colleagues.

### Key Skills:

- Design leadership: coaching, mentoring, line management
- Interaction design: prototyping
- Service design: service mapping
- Stakeholder management and engagement

Apps:

Adobe Creative Suite Axure

Sketch app

Frontend:

HTML, CSS, Jquery, PHP, Nunjucks

## Experience

**UK Home Office** 

11 months

Lead Interaction Designer (interim)

October 2021 - Present (4 months)

Sheffield, England, United Kingdom

In my short time at the Home Office I have led design work in areas of 2 high profile projects, as well as interim design lead in UCD Ops with a focus on the Home Office design system, which contains guidance and standards for Home Office services. I have led recruitment to build the UCD function in a portfolio of the Home Office while line managing other members of the UCD community.

Senior Interaction Designer

March 2021 - November 2021 (9 months)

NHS Digital

3 years 7 months

Senior Interaction Designer

November 2019 - March 2021 (1 year 5 months)

Interaction designer on the NHS screening service

Senior Interaction Designer

December 2018 - October 2019 (11 months)

Leeds, United Kingdom

Interaction designer on the NHS e-Referral Service.

Senior Interaction Designer

September 2017 - December 2018 (1 year 4 months)

Leeds, West Yorkshire, United Kingdom

Providing design leadership to the nhs digital web team; educating and involving the team in agile and design thinking processes, through discovery and alpha phases: researching, prototyping and testing. I also spent 3 months seconded to a product ownership role which has given me a wider perspective and experience on product development and team leadership.

FinancialForce

Senior UX Designer

October 2016 - September 2017 (1 year)

Harrogate, United Kingdom

User research: Contextual enquiry, user interviews, survey design, usability testing. Prototyping, visual design, persona creation and documentation.

Sky Betting & Gaming

Senior Experience Architect

December 2015 - November 2016 (1 year)

Using hypothesis driven design methods to validate ideas from discovery to delivery. Providing user research, interviewing customers, moderating lab based user testing every 2 weeks as part of the agile discovery phase. Providing prototypes for testing, working with visual designers to agree on use of correct design patterns. Presenting findings back to tribe via talks and presentations, facilitating design workshops to share ideas.

DAZN Group UX Architect

October 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 3 months)

Leeds

Introduced and led all UX research and usability test planning and implementation across all projects. Other responsibilities: User/stakeholder interviews, quantitive data analysis, persona building, user journeys, wireframing, html prototyping, design workshop facilitation. Where possible this was done on a per project basis. Introduced colleagues and stakeholders to guerilla research methods, persona building and user story mapping. Helped and mentored younger members of the UX team.

#### Civica

**UX/UI** Designer

December 2013 - December 2014 (1 year 1 month)

UX team of one: undertook user research, persona creation, design workshop facilitation, wireframing, mockups, prototyping and user testing, user interviews, front end development, research reports and recommendations, user journey planning, storyboarding, responsive design.

Jet2.com

Senior Web UX/UI Designer

October 2011 - December 2013 (2 years 3 months)

Co managed a web team of 5. Led UX/design for travel guide project which involved design, prototyping, usability testing and iteration, SEO and social strategy.

Rocom

Web Designer

October 2009 - July 2011 (1 year 10 months)

Manheim Europe

Web Designer

December 2007 - October 2009 (1 year 11 months)

Hill Dickinson LLP

Web Designer

September 2006 - December 2007 (1 year 4 months)

# Education

The Open University

Bachelor's Degree, Industrial and Product Design · (2011 - 2019)

The Manchester College

HND, Multimedia Computing and Design · (2001 - 2003)